Contact

+91-9991005418 (Mobile) sachin.arora1650@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/ sachinarorasfdc (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Programming Languages
Java
Computer Science

Languages

English (Professional Working)

Certifications

Java SE 6 Programmer Certified Professional Salesforce Developer Certified Scrum Master

Sachin Arora

Scrum Master and Principal Solutions Architect at Cloud Analogy South West Delhi, Delhi, India

Summary

An IT professional with a breadth and depth of software design and development experience. With over 6 years of experience in the IT field, I have had the privilege of working in varied hardware and software environments ranging from Honeywell & IBM Mainframes, Enterprise Java, PLM technologies, RFID, Cloud technologies such as Salesforce, AWS, Cloud Foundry & Google App Engine and Mobile. My range of experience helps me connect well and communicate appropriately with associates ranging from developer to senior management. Industry exp. offered me wonderful opportunities to travel and work in various locations as well as contribute to client success with contributions at various levels ranging from developer, transition manager to architect.

I believe in continuous learning and am always on the lookout to add that new skill to my arsenal or the opportunity to utilize my skills.

Experience

CloudAnalogy
Principal Solutions Architect
October 2017 - Present
Noida Area, India

HIC Global Solutions (ex Head in Cloud Inc) Lead Developer October 2015 - September 2017 (2 years)

Noida Area, India

Drive and increase user adoption and ensure user satisfaction, including developing, documenting and delivering training.

*Develop and maintain report folders, dashboards, etc. to improve system usability.

*Maintain a holistic view of all business processes and users in the system to understand cross functional impacts with regard to configuration, process, workflow and reporting.

- *Lead / Assist with user requirement sessions and document user requirements to address changing business needs.
- Collaborate with offshore team
- Co-ordinate with customer, product vendors and other stake IT Teams
- Maintain high level of competence in tool in order to quickly provide accurate high level cost and schedule impacts of each proposed solution.
- Communicate effectively with both business Subject Matter Experts and technical design and developers.
- Co-ordinate with customer, product vendors and other IT stakeholders from both technical and non-technical communities

Algoworks

Software Engineer

August 2014 - September 2015 (1 year 2 months)

Monitors and updates Salesforce Certification requirements for employees which includes training and advancement opportunities needed for continuous partnership with Salesforce.com and its product lines.

Align Sales Process to Salesforce.com CRM to increase lead conversion, and sales conversion.

Implemented the New Lightning User Interface to the entire Sales Organization after a change management plan, training and project implementation. Interface with potential clients and existing customers as trusted advisor for implementations and support for Salesforce Marketing Cloud and other integration use cases.

Conduct product demonstrations on Tech Solutions Review for potential clients and existing businesses on new product releases and key features of Marketing Cloud Email, Social Studio, Advertising Studio and Marketing Cloud Builders.

I have worked on Java and SQL and Currently working on Salesforce Technology

AlmaMate Info Tech

Salesforce Trainee

August 2013 - July 2014 (1 year)

- Hands-on experience in configuration, customization and integration of Salesforce
- Hands-on experience on Service and Sales Cloud
- Experience with configuration and customization using Visual Force and Apex.

Arcolympians
Software Trainer
August 2012 - July 2013 (1 year)

Education

Kurukshetra University

Bachelor of Technology (B.Tech.), Computer Engineering · (2008 - 2012)